<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wanderings | A blog</title><link>http://blog.hacktohell.org/</link><description>Recent content on Wanderings | A blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 | Follow on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hacktohell" target="_blank">Twitter&lt;/a></copyright><atom:link href="http://blog.hacktohell.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Controlling Mitsubushi Heat Pump with esphome and homeassistant</title><link>http://blog.hacktohell.org/mitsubishi-ac-heat-pump-esphome-homeassistant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:49:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.hacktohell.org/mitsubishi-ac-heat-pump-esphome-homeassistant/</guid><description>Modern heat pumps are incredibly efficient and can be used to heat and cool your home, however there&amp;rsquo;s still the matter of controlling them precisely to how your would want your house. With it being more decrentalized especially with minisplits, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit more tricky to &amp;ldquo;nest&amp;rdquo; them. I wanted to have a somewhat automated climate controller that meant automatic switch on when the temperature is too low and switch off when the temperature is too high as well as using an external temperature sensor to control the temperature.</description></item><item><title>Main Desktop Build and Pain Points</title><link>http://blog.hacktohell.org/main-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:49:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.hacktohell.org/main-build/</guid><description>Documenting my current main desktop build.
Component Description Price CPU 3900x 100? Motherboard ASUS AM4 TUF Gaming X570-Plus 214 PSU MONTECH Titan Gold 1200W 189 Fans ARCTIC P12 PWM PST 40 RAM G.SKILL Ripjaws V DDR4 RAM 64GB (2x32GB) 3600MT/S 129 Case CORSAIR 4000D 89.99 GPU Nvidia Founder Edition 3070 600 GPU Zotac GeForce RTX 3090 Trinity (used) 760 Cooler Liquid Freezer II 240 86 Total 2207.</description></item><item><title>NAS and selfhosted server build</title><link>http://blog.hacktohell.org/nas-server-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 04:38:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.hacktohell.org/nas-server-build/</guid><description>While I have officially had a whole load of smaller machines as &amp;ldquo;selfhosted&amp;rdquo; servers, they have been adhoc all over the place (raspis are quite fun to stick in random places and then forget about). I have also been running on some older laptop hard drives that finally kicked the bucket and I don&amp;rsquo;t have space on my main rig anymore after fiting a 3090 and a 3070 in it.</description></item><item><title>Making VP9 hardware decoding work with Kaby Lake and Arch Linux</title><link>http://blog.hacktohell.org/vp9-hardware-decoding-arch-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 19:51:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.hacktohell.org/vp9-hardware-decoding-arch-linux/</guid><description>Kaby Lake processors come with Intel HD graphics chips that allows for you to do hardware decoding of VP9 and H.265 10 bit videos. Check the chart below for more details.
Intel Allows you to access their Intel GPU by using the VA-API, the Arch Linux wiki has a good deal of information on VA-API and VDPAU here.
Installing Drivers Let&amp;rsquo;s install the VA-API with
sudo pacman -S libva-intel-driver</description></item><item><title>Moving from HDD to SSD with Arch Linux</title><link>http://blog.hacktohell.org/moving-from-hdd-to-ssd-arch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 13:51:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.hacktohell.org/moving-from-hdd-to-ssd-arch/</guid><description>Was scouting out a SSD for my laptop and I found the 2 year old EVO 850 series to be the right combination of performance vs reliability. I got the 250 GB one as it was within my 10k budget. I also got a metal mounting bracket, (plastic ones don&amp;rsquo;t conduct heat). Originally the plan was to have the HDD in the bracket but ended up having the SSD in there.</description></item><item><title>Adding multi level commands using spf13 cobra</title><link>http://blog.hacktohell.org/multi-level-command-spf13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 17:34:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.hacktohell.org/multi-level-command-spf13/</guid><description>We can chain commands pretty simply, say you want to make an app streamer that has a sub command read and an sub-command of that called csv and json. You can use the cobra init to generate these separate ones,
cobra add csv cobra add json
cobra add read
Then go into the source file and hook up csv and json with the proper parent, in this case, readCmd.</description></item></channel></rss>